<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: quotes | Archome]]></title>
  <link href="http://archo.me/blog/categories/quotes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archo.me/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-22T23:17:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archo.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Archome]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Professional Tyranny]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/02/29/professional-tyranny/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T14:24:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/02/29/professional-tyranny</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>The wandering physician became the medical doctor when he left commerce in drugs to the pharmacist and kept for himself the power to prescribe them. At that moment, he acquired a new kind of authority by uniting three roles in one person: the sapiental authority to advise, instruct and direct; the moral authority that makes its acceptance not just useful but obligatory; and the charismatic authority that allows the physician to appeal to some supreme interest of his clients that not only outranks conscience but sometimes even the "raison d'état." ...</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>The difference between craftsman, liberal professional and the new technocrat can be clarified by comparing the typical reaction of people who neglect their respective advice. If you did not take the craftsman's advice, you were a fool. If you did not take liberal counsel, society blamed you. Now the profession or government may be blamed when you escape from the care that your lawyer, teacher, surgeon or shrink has decided upon for you. Under the pretense of meeting needs better and on a more equitable basis, the service-professional has mutated into a crusading philanthropist. ...</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Professionals claim a monopoly over the definition of deviance and the remedies needed. For example, lawyers assert that they alone have the competence and legal right to provide assistance in divorce. If you devise a kit for do-it-yourself divorce, you find yourself in a double bind: if you are not a lawyer, you are liable of practice without a license; if you are a member of the bar, you can be expelled for unprofessional behaviour ... Morticians formed a profession, a dominant and disabling one, when they acquired the muscle to have police stop your burial if you are not embalmed and boxed by them. In any area where a human need can be imagined, these new disabling professions claim that they are the exclusive experts of the public good.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>
Illich, Ivan. 1978. <i>The Right To Useful Unemployment and Its Professional Enemies</i>. Marion Boyars.
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Preservation of Monopolistic Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/02/27/the-preservation-of-monopolistic-control/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T18:57:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/02/27/the-preservation-of-monopolistic-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>Skilled blue-collar workers were the bearers of a quite different culture. They were craftsmen who wielded complex skills (partly manual, partly intellectual) on which production processes were highly dependent and on which the income, status and power of the craftsmen, both in the workplace and in the household, rested. Consequently, their greatest preoccupation was the preservation of their monopolistic control over production know-how. This preoccupation identified their interests with those of self-employed craftsmen, made them suspicious of unskilled workers, and was a continuous source of antagonism towards the attempts of the capitalist employers to break the monopolistic practices of these craftsmen through deskilling innovations.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>
Arrighi, Giovanni, Terence K. Hopkins, and Immanuel Wallerstein. 2012. <i>Anti-Systemic Movements</i>. Verso Books.
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
