<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Archome]]></title>
  <link href="http://archo.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archo.me/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-05T14:39:32-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archo.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Archome]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Energy and Equity]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/04/22/notes-on-energy-and-equity/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T22:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/04/22/notes-on-energy-and-equity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The essays in this book, often connected by tenuous thematic threads, argue that the unequal consumption of energy is the sign of other forms of inequity and that the divide between &#8220;first world&#8221; and &#8220;third world&#8221; nations is marked by vast differences in production and consumption of energy.</p>

<p>Ilich distinguishes between two forms of traffic; transit and transport. The former uses &#8220;metabolic energy&#8221; to move people from place to place, while the latter uses other forms of energy, for example motors.</p>

<p>He further argues that past a certain point, the consumption of energy in the service of transport actually constricts human movement by shaping social and economic relations and forcing humans to spend increased time in compulsory transport. This argument can be compared to Virilio&#8217;s discussion of the regulation of transportation and speed as a primary form of social control.</p>

<p>This book also provides an extension of Ilich&#8217;s earlier work on convivial technology through his dicussion of &#8220;mature technology,&#8221; which is the middle ground between overindustrialization and underequipment.</p>

<blockquote><p>There are two roads from where we are to technological maturity: one is the road of liberation from affluence; the other is the road of liberation from dependence. Both roads have the same destination: the social restructuring of space that offers to each person the constantly renewed experience that the centre of the world is where he stands, walks and lives.</p></blockquote>


<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join&#8217; for #&lt;String:0x00000102885c18></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Paul Mishler's Raising Reds]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/03/18/notes-on-raising-reds/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T15:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/03/18/notes-on-raising-reds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Documents the concerns of the Communist family and education in the United States.</p>

<p>Mishler proposes that Communist education draws from two strains of radical education in the US: socialist and anarchist. Anarchist education more concerned with radicalizing structure of education; socialist education focuses on radicalizing content of classes. Communist education attempts to synthesize both these traditions and further them by engaging children&#8217;s organizations in active political activity. Tension between transcending ethnicity in favor &#8220;Americanism&#8221; while still maintaining radical tradition (which were largely rooted in European ethnic groups).</p>

<p>Young Pioneer summer camps &#8220;provided an institutional setting where a Communist political culture could be developed away from the hostility of the larger society,&#8221; particularly in the absence of strikes or other demonstrations around which to organize children (55). Organized by coalitions of Young Pioneers, Workers International Relief (strike organizing) and fraternal left wing ethnic societies. Camps were usually 25-30 children that stayed for one to two weeks. Structure of camp models socialist society. Thinking there are some interesting parallels here: replace ethnic group with professional group; American with Information Professional.</p>

<p>International Workers Order was successful because it primarily celebrated radical ethnicity; socialism was woven into the background of many of its activities and content. Does an emphasis on ethnicity lead to radicalization of children, or are ethnic groups conservative by nature? Tension between assimilation and conservatism of remaining in your ethnic group.</p>

<blockquote><p>The camps were arenas where culture was created, not simply educational institutions, because of the relationship between the organized educational activities and the space between the organized activities. In this space, children created their own &#8220;feeling&#8221; for the camps. The informal and undirected times were as politically important as activities directed toward communicating a specific political message. To feel comfortable, in their own setting, was a unique experience for the children of radicals, whose families&#8217; values were at odds with those of the dominant culture. The programs and activities of the camp promoted values and an ideology in tune with the beliefs the children were taught at home. At the same time, the absence of hostility toward those beliefs became one of the utopian elements in the camps.</p></blockquote>


<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join&#8217; for #&lt;String:0x00000102b428e8></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Nature of Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/03/10/on-the-nature-of-time/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-10T18:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/03/10/on-the-nature-of-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Indeed the future has already broken into the present. We live in many times. The present of one is the past of another, and the future of yet another. We are called to live, knowing and showing that the future exists and that each one of us can call it in, when we are willing, to redress the balance of the past.</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>&#8230;the marking off of temporal boundaries, what archivists (and historians) call &#8220;context,&#8221; is less straightforward than it often seems. Not only does each of us, and each community, occupy various territorial spaces; each of us, and each community, also experiences, is inhabited by, multiple temporal (time) zones. Indeed, archivists have perhaps given the concept of context, that most precious of often-unacknowledged archival gifts to the information studies community, more work, or perhaps less, to do than it can really perform. (423)</p></blockquote>


<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join&#8217; for #&lt;String:0x00000102c88a18></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Speed and Politics]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/03/05/notes-on-speed-and-politics/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-05T18:50:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/03/05/notes-on-speed-and-politics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Masses are not defined by relation to production, but by their unpredictable and unregulated &#8220;circulation&#8221; (3). &#8220;Revolution is movement, but movement is not a revolution&#8221; (18); as a result the restriction of movement (through legislation, ghettoization, militarization and consumption) is the means by which revolution is suppressed. Revolution is therefore an &#8220;assault on time&#8221; and safety lies not in fleeing but attacking literally before your opponent has the opportunity to destroy you (22).</p>

<blockquote><p>Everything in this new warfare becomes a question of time won by man over the fatal projectiles toward which his path throws him. Speed is Time saved in the absolute sense of the word, since it becomes human Time directly torn from Death&#8230;</p></blockquote>


<p>The establishment of cities at places of strategic importance led to their fortification, a phenomenon which both implies and invites a constant state of siege (15). This state of siege has been expanded both horizontally and vertically to a state of emergency through the growth (and ownership) of the seas and airspace and the undetectability of attackers (38, 40). The vague and constant state of emergency described by Virilio is reminiscent of the paranoia and defensive actions resulting from the actions of collectives like Anonymous and Wikileaks.</p>

<blockquote><p>Hitler, like Napoleon, will be defeated by the fleet in being, which will constantly draw its victory from its inaccessibility to combat, from its abandonment of the harmful principle that we must attack as soon as the enemy is in sight, that we must shorten the distance between them and us. The fleet in being is logistics taking strategy to its absolute point, as is the art of movement of unseen bodies; it is the permanent presence in the sea of an invisible fleet able to strike no matter where and no matter when, annihilating the enemy&#8217;s will to power by creating a global zone of insecurity in which it will no longer be able to &#8220;decide&#8221; with certainty, to want&#8211;in other words, to win.</p></blockquote>


<p>Technology produces faster and more efficient machines, which in turn speed up the process of technological innovation. Peace is only achieved through the over-driving and collapse of this process (46).</p>

<blockquote><p>It is speed as the nature of dromological progress that ruins progress; it is the permanance of the war of Time that creates total peace, the peace of exhaustion.</p></blockquote>


<p>Speed is the dividing line between East and West, North and South, and between those with hope and those without (47).</p>

<blockquote><p>With the realization of dromocratic-type progress, humanity will stop being diverse. It will tend to divide only into hopeful populations (who are allowed the hope that they will reach, in the future, someday, the speed that they are accumulating, which will give them access to the possible&#8211;that is, to the project, the decision, the infinite: speed is the hope of the West) and despairing populations, blocked by the inferiority of their technological vehicles, living and subsisting in a finite world.</p></blockquote>


<p>Unsurprisingly, Virilio states that the natural outgrowth of a world system built on a hierarchy of speed is fascism (117).</p>

<p>The need for security has been manipulated into a form of consumption (122, 127). Since violence can be reduced to movement (40), security can therefore be defined as the absence of movement (125).</p>

<blockquote><p>We will see the creation of a common feeling of insecurity that will lead to a new kind of consumption, the consumption of protection; this latter will progressively come to the fore and become the target of the whole merchandising system&#8230;.The indivisible promotion of the need for security already composes a new composite portrait of the citizen&#8211;no longer the one who enriches the nation by consuming, but the one who invests first and foremost in security, manages his own protection as best he can, and finally pays more to consume less.</p></blockquote>


<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join&#8217; for #&lt;String:0x00000100fb1110></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Professional Tyranny]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/02/29/professional-tyranny/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T14:24:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/02/29/professional-tyranny</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The wandering physician became the medical doctor when he left commerce in drugs to the pharmacist and kept for himself the power to prescribe them. At that moment, he acquired a new kind of authority by uniting three roles in one person: the sapiental authority to advise, instruct and direct; the moral authority that makes its acceptance not just useful but obligatory; and the charismatic authority that allows the physician to appeal to some supreme interest of his clients that not only outranks conscience but sometimes even the &#8220;raison d&#8217;état.&#8221; &#8230;</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>The difference between craftsman, liberal professional and the new technocrat can be clarified by comparing the typical reaction of people who neglect their respective advice. If you did not take the craftsman&#8217;s advice, you were a fool. If you did not take liberal counsel, society blamed you. Now the profession or government may be blamed when you escape from the care that your lawyer, teacher, surgeon or shrink has decided upon for you. Under the pretense of meeting needs better and on a more equitable basis, the service-professional has mutated into a crusading philanthropist. &#8230;</p></blockquote>




<blockquote><p>Professionals claim a monopoly over the definition of deviance and the remedies needed. For example, lawyers assert that they alone have the competence and legal right to provide assistance in divorce. If you devise a kit for do-it-yourself divorce, you find yourself in a double bind: if you are not a lawyer, you are liable of practice without a license; if you are a member of the bar, you can be expelled for unprofessional behaviour &#8230; Morticians formed a profession, a dominant and disabling one, when they acquired the muscle to have police stop your burial if you are not embalmed and boxed by them. In any area where a human need can be imagined, these new disabling professions claim that they are the exclusive experts of the public good.</p></blockquote>


<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join&#8217; for #&lt;String:0x0000010287d3b0></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Preservation of Monopolistic Control]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/02/27/the-preservation-of-monopolistic-control/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T18:57:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/02/27/the-preservation-of-monopolistic-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Skilled blue-collar workers were the bearers of a quite different culture. They were craftsmen who wielded complex skills (partly manual, partly intellectual) on which production processes were highly dependent and on which the income, status and power of the craftsmen, both in the workplace and in the household, rested. Consequently, their greatest preoccupation was the preservation of their monopolistic control over production know-how. This preoccupation identified their interests with those of self-employed craftsmen, made them suspicious of unskilled workers, and was a continuous source of antagonism towards the attempts of the capitalist employers to break the monopolistic practices of these craftsmen through deskilling innovations.</p></blockquote>


<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join&#8217; for #&lt;String:0x00000102b16f68></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Wolfgang Ernst's "Media Archaeography"]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/02/26/media-archaeography/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-26T21:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/02/26/media-archaeography</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wolfgang Ernst&#8217;s (2011) presentation of &#8220;media archaeology&#8221; situates it as a methodological and aesthetic approach that is, in his description, preferable over &#8220;the supremacy of media-historical narratives.&#8221; In Ernst&#8217;s account, the media itself gains a certain level of agency:</p>

<blockquote><p>[Media archaeology &#8230;] is an awareness when media themselves, *not just humans anymore,* become active &#8220;archaeologists&#8221; of knowledge.</p></blockquote>


<p>In the words of Parikka (2011): <em>it is the machine in which the past gets archived as a monument and that is the true subject of technical media culture.</em> Not only does media become its own archaeologist, in a sense media buries itself alive.</p>

<p>Ernst seems to suggest that media archaeology that focuses on the analysis epistemological relationships has a greater potential for subversive or oppositional discourse when media are understood as participating or belonging across other temporal spaces. Parikka (2011) argues, however, that Ernst has not leveraged this potential to its fullest extent.</p>

<p>Ernst&#8217;s media-archaelogical approach thus seems possible in part because its objects — artifacts — persist across time(s) and always have the possibility of being <em>reactivated</em>:</p>

<blockquote><p>The phonograph as media artifact not only culture cultural meanings like words and music but is at the same time an archive of cultural engineering by its very material fabrication—a kind of frozen media knowledge that—in a media-archaelogical sense—is waiting to be unfrozen, liquified.</p></blockquote>


<p>This &#8220;frozenness&#8221; of media also seems to concern its seeming indifference with the semantic content that it carries. Media operate at a level below—or beyond?—concern for the message interpretable by humans. For Parikka, this focus on the &#8220;micro-temporal&#8221; or &#8220;time-critical&#8221; is what distinguishes the German from the Anglo-American approaches to media archaeology.</p>

<p>Is it that media function at a level of granularity such that patterns are insignificant? Are the time-critical microöperations themselves so devoid of context that they are unintelligible? This can be compared with MacNeil&#8217;s (1995) distinction between archival description and metadata in the context of electronic records:</p>

<blockquote><p>Because the context revealed by metadata systems is so detailed, and the volume of transactions they capture so enormous, metadata may in fact obscure, rather than illuminate, the broader administrative context and thereby bias the users&#8217; understanding of the records&#8217; meaning.</p></blockquote>


<p>This media-archaelogical approach may prove unsettling for some archivists for precisely this reason. Archives themselves become less &#8220;special&#8221; as they are transformed into registers or addresses—a <em>non-lieux</em> of Marc Augé—through which we and media pass (cf. Trace&#8217;s (2011) adaptation of Feynman&#8217;s  file-clerk model of computing).</p>

<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join&#8217; for #&lt;String:0x00000102cae740></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
