<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: education | Archome]]></title>
  <link href="http://archome.github.com/archome/blog/categories/education/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archome.github.com/archome/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-18T18:56:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archome.github.com/archome/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Archome]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Paul Mishler's Raising Reds]]></title>
    <link href="http://archome.github.com/archome/2012/03/18/notes-on-raising-reds/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T15:55:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archome.github.com/archome/2012/03/18/notes-on-raising-reds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Documents the concerns of the Communist family and education in the United States.</p>

<p>Mishler proposes that Communist education draws from two strains of radical education in the US: socialist and anarchist. Anarchist education more concerned with radicalizing structure of education; socialist education focuses on radicalizing content of classes. Communist education attempts to synthesize both these traditions and further them by engaging children's organizations in active political activity. Tension between transcending ethnicity in favor "Americanism" while still maintaining radical tradition (which were largely rooted in European ethnic groups).</p>

<p>Young Pioneer summer camps "provided an institutional setting where a Communist political culture could be developed away from the hostility of the larger society," particularly in the absence of strikes or other demonstrations around which to organize children (55). Organized by coalitions of Young Pioneers, Workers International Relief (strike organizing) and fraternal left wing ethnic societies. Camps were usually 25-30 children that stayed for one to two weeks. Structure of camp models socialist society. Thinking there are some interesting parallels here: replace ethnic group with professional group; American with Information Professional.</p>

<p>International Workers Order was successful because it primarily celebrated radical ethnicity; socialism was woven into the background of many of its activities and content. Does an emphasis on ethnicity lead to radicalization of children, or are ethnic groups conservative by nature? Tension between assimilation and conservatism of remaining in your ethnic group.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The camps were arenas where culture was created, not simply educational institutions, because of the relationship between the organized educational activities and the space between the organized activities. In this space, children created their own "feeling" for the camps. The informal and undirected times were as politically important as activities directed toward communicating a specific political message. To feel comfortable, in their own setting, was a unique experience for the children of radicals, whose families' values were at odds with those of the dominant culture. The programs and activities of the camp promoted values and an ideology in tune with the beliefs the children were taught at home. At the same time, the absence of hostility toward those beliefs became one of the utopian elements in the camps.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>
Mishler, Paul C. 1999. <i>Raising Reds: the Young Pioneers, Radical Summer Camps, and Communist Political Culture In the United States</i>. Columbia Univ Pr.
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
