<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: time | Archome]]></title>
  <link href="http://archo.me/blog/categories/time/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archo.me/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-22T23:17:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archo.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Archome]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Nature of Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/03/10/on-the-nature-of-time/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-10T18:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/03/10/on-the-nature-of-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><blockquote><p>Indeed the future has already broken into the present. We live in many times. The present of one is the past of another, and the future of yet another. We are called to live, knowing and showing that the future exists and that each one of us can call it in, when we are willing, to redress the balance of the past.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>...the marking off of temporal boundaries, what archivists (and historians) call "context," is less straightforward than it often seems. Not only does each of us, and each community, occupy various territorial spaces; each of us, and each community, also experiences, is inhabited by, multiple temporal (time) zones. Indeed, archivists have perhaps given the concept of context, that most precious of often-unacknowledged archival gifts to the information studies community, more work, or perhaps less, to do than it can really perform. (423)</p></blockquote></p>

<p>
Illich, Ivan D. 1970. <i>Celebration of Awareness: A Call For Institutional Revolution</i>. Inc. Doubleday and Company.</p>

<p>Brothman, B. 2011. “The Society of American Archivists At Seventy-Five: Contexts of Continuity and Crisis, A Personal Reflection”. <i>American Archivist</i> 74 (2): 423.
</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
