<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: energy | Archome]]></title>
  <link href="http://archo.me/blog/categories/energy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://archo.me/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-05T14:39:32-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://archo.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Archome]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notes on Energy and Equity]]></title>
    <link href="http://archo.me/2012/04/22/notes-on-energy-and-equity/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T22:54:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://archo.me/2012/04/22/notes-on-energy-and-equity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The essays in this book, often connected by tenuous thematic threads, argue that the unequal consumption of energy is the sign of other forms of inequity and that the divide between "first world" and "third world" nations is marked by vast differences in production and consumption of energy.</p>

<p>Ilich distinguishes between two forms of traffic; transit and transport. The former uses "metabolic energy" to move people from place to place, while the latter uses other forms of energy, for example motors.</p>

<p>He further argues that past a certain point, the consumption of energy in the service of transport actually constricts human movement by shaping social and economic relations and forcing humans to spend increased time in compulsory transport. This argument can be compared to Virilio's discussion of the regulation of transportation and speed as a primary form of social control.</p>

<p>This book also provides an extension of Ilich's earlier work on convivial technology through his dicussion of "mature technology," which is the middle ground between overindustrialization and underequipment.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>There are two roads from where we are to technological maturity: one is the road of liberation from affluence; the other is the road of liberation from dependence. Both roads have the same destination: the social restructuring of space that offers to each person the constantly renewed experience that the centre of the world is where he stands, walks and lives.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Liquid error: undefined method `join' for #<String:0x00000100f6b2a0></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
